## Mary Melgar

Email: marylauramelgar@gmail.com 50 Biscayne Blvd., Miami, FL, 33132

#### **SUMMARY**

Multitasking and proficient Human Resources Professional with direct operations and payroll management experience. With over 10 years of experience leading organizational development, communications and human resources initiatives that support strategic business results and link human assets to business outcome. A professional who operates as a key business partner providing leadership to the organization and executive team. Experienced at identifying and executing cost control initiatives. Proactive leader who brings talented applicants and fulfills the function through personal integrity, leadership, and professional expertise.

### PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

#### **Director of Human Resources - VMR Products LLC.**

09/2013 - 01/2019

- Promoted to fulfill and manage all functions of the Human Resources Department in Miami, China and Czech Republic.
- Strategic Talent Attraction, Management and Retention.
- Strategic orientation and on-boarding process that ensures a solid start for all employees.
- Developing and implementing company policies and procedures.
- **Employee relations Management**

Phone: 305-321-6103.

- Implementation of proactive measures and reactive procedures to identify risk and reduce cost.
- Managing Benefits and Compensation programs that provides a great return on investment.
- Developing and maintaining an effective strategy to ensure the organization is in labor compliance.
- Maintaining and promoting a Safety and Healthy Work Environment
- Work closely with immigration lawyers preparing applications and fulfilling all Visa requirements for international emplovees.
- Conduct comprehensive exit interviews, analyze the information gathered and implement a strategic plan to reduce
- Strategic Performance Management

## Manager of Communications and Public Relations - GNTP

01/2008 - 12/2011

- Promoted to fulfill Communication and Media needs of the organization by promoting citizen's participation in the process of economic and sustainable development
- Corporate image renovation and Management
- **Public Relations Management**
- Website Administrator and Writer
- Corporate Magazine Editor and Writer
- Corporate Events organization

### Student Council's President of Communications – NUR University

01/ 2006 - 12/2007

- Events organization and administration
- Promote student's welfare, educational quality and educational rights
- Fundraiser for the career events and charity, especially for students with economic problems or those who had severe illness.

## Editor and writer - Generation 21, NUR University

01/2005 - 12/2005

Miami, FL - 08/2017

- Newspaper administration, organization and edition
- News information researcher
- Writer

# **EDUCATION**

- Master in Human Resources Management Florida International University
- Certification in Human Resources Management University of Miami.
- Bachelor Degree in Social Communications and Journalism NUR University
- Miami, FL 12/2013
- Santa Cruz, Bolivia 12/2010

#### **SKILLS**

- Human Resources Management
- **Team Management**
- Talent attraction and retention
- Business Strategy
- Employee Relations and Labor Compliance
- Internal and External Communications
- Labor Compliance Management
- Excellent verbal and written communication skills
- Strong organizational and analytical skills
- Pavroll Management
- Strategic Benefits and Compensation Management
- International HR Management
- · Proficient in Microsoft Office
- · Bilingual; English and Spanish